Siyi Liu

Email: siyiliu@seas.upenn.edu
Github: github.com/liusiyi641

Research Interests

My primary research interest lies in the intersection of machine learning and natural language understanding. I am generally interested in understanding the implications from news sources, including their *perspectives* and *frames*. I am also interested in multi-modality learning, low resource/zero-shot NLP, NLP for social good, and other applications of NLP.

Education

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

2020-2022

M.S.E. in Computer and Information Science

Advisor: Dan Roth

Boston University, Boston, MA

2016-2020

B.A./M.S. Dual Degree in Computer Science

Advisor: Derry Wijaya

Publications

[1] Siyi Liu, Sihao Chen, Xander Uyttendaele, Dan Roth

"MultiOpEd: A Corpus of Multi-Perspective News Editorials", in NAACL 2021.

[Paper][Slides/Talk/Poster]

[2] Siyi Liu, Lei Guo, Kate Mays, Margrit Betke and Derry Tanti Wijaya.

"Detecting Frames in News Headlines and Its Application to Analyzing News Framing Trends Surrounding U.S. Gun Violence." In *Proceedings of Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning* (CoNLL) 2019.

[Paper] [Slides]

[3] Siyi Liu*, Ziang Leng*, Derry Tanti Wijaya.

"Learning To Mirror Speaking Styles Incrementally." in arxiv.

Paper]

Research Experience

University of Pennsylvania

Summer 2020 – Present

Advisor: Prof. Dan Roth

Project: Information Pollution Project

- A dataset with hierarchical structure of query, perspectives, evidence, article
- Study and analyze the argumentation structure of news articles
- Develop a demo website that searches in real time in a perspective-oriented manner
- Argument similarity with sentence compression

University of Pennsylvania

Fall 2021 - Present

Advisor: Prof. Mark Yatskar

Project: Zero-shot Image Classification with Pre-trained Text Representations

- Pretrain language models on Wikipedia articles and produce text representations as side-information
- Align image and text representations for zero-shot image classification

Boston University

Spring 2019 – Fall 2020

Advisor: Prof. Derry Wijaya

- *Projects:*
 - Detect frames in news headlines and analyze news framing trends surrounding U.S. gun violence
 - Capture and transform speaking styles in a low resource setting
 - Create multimedia summaries using tweets and videos

City University of Hong Kong

Advisor: Prof. Junhui Wang Aug 2019 - Sep 2019

Project: Analyze Chinese law documents and cluster similar case descriptions

Awards

Undergraduate Research Opportunity Program Award, Boston University Fall 2019 Dean's List, College of Arts and Sciences, Boston University Spring 2019 Dean's List, College of Arts and Sciences, Boston University Spring 2018

Skills

Programming Languages: Python (proficient), Java, C/C++, Latex

Tools: Huggingface Transformers, Pytorch, nltk, sklearn

Services

Reviewers: AAAI 2021 (secondary)